Weston Woods Studios Collection 2004.0141
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Weston Woods Studios Collection
undated, 1974-2004
2004.0141
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
1.0 Linear feet
The collection contains animation celluloids used in the creation of children's filmstrips by the Weston Woods Studio located in Weston, Connecticut.
Weston Woods Studios.
Provenance and Acquisition
The collection was donated in 2004 by Morton Schindel, founder of Weston Woods Studio.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
History
Weston Woods was founded in 1953 by Morton Schindel who became fascinated with picture books while reading to his children. He was inspired by their involvement with the stories and the rapt attention they paid to the illustrations and their eagerness to listen to a story over and over again. Weston Woods has remained the principal innovator in the translation of picture books into the audiovisual media, and the pioneer of the multimedia approach to children's literature. Throughout this time, the philosophical underpinning of Weston Woods has been fidelity to the original. In 1996, Weston Woods became part of Scholastic, Inc. Partnership with Scholastic Inc., the world's largest publisher of children's books, provided the opportunity to support literacy around the world. Since the founding of each of these companies, Scholastic and Weston Woods have shared a common vision: To provide educators with the best possible learning tools to enhance positive learning experiences and to instill in children a lifelong love of books and reading. (source: http://westonwoods.scholastic.com/products/westonwoods/mission.htm).
Scope and content
The collection contains 25 animation celluloids used in the creation of children's filmstrips by the Weston Woods Studio located in Weston, Connecticut. The collection includes individual cels for many well-known filmstrips such as Where the Wild Things Are, Moon Man, and Here Comes Cat, as well as the certificates of authenticity for each cel. The collection also contains a folder of promotional materials celebrating the 50th anniversary of Weston Woods including two VHS tapes ( Where the Wild Things Are and From Page to Screen: Celebrating 50 Years of Bringing Books to Life)
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Schindel, Morton; Children's literature—Illustrations.; Northeast Children's Literature Collection.
- Series I: Inventory, undated, 1974-2004
  - Celluloid illustrations, Promotional materials, undated, 1974-2004 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Includes: Dates: N.D., 1975, 1978, 1982, 1987, 1989, 1991, 1992, 1993, 2003, 2004 Organization: animation cels each contained in large envelopes, each with a taped certificate of authenticity attached. Cels vaguely grouped by movie. Other materials on top of cels due to smaller size/weight. Subjects: Packet of fliers/promotional items about Weston Woods 50 anniversary of making animated movies of children’s books. Photocopied article about Northeast Children’s Literature Collection. Hand painted cels from various motion picture adaptations of children’s books: “Winnie & Fox” from Wings a Tale of Two Chickens movie, based on book by James Marshall “The Scientist” from Moon Man movie, based on book by Tomi Ungerer “Self Portrait” from Here Comes Cat! movie, based on book by Frank Asch “Bear Under Tree” from Happy Birthday Moon movie, based on book by Frank Asch “Harold draws Bird” from Harold’s Fairytale movie, based on book by Crockett Johnson “The Wild Thing” signed by Rudolph Holan, from Where the Wild Things Are movie, based on book by Maurice Sendak “Bakers around Pot” from In the Night Kitchen movie, based on book by Maurice Sendak “Mickey in the Milk Bottle” from In the Night Kitchen movie, based on book by Maurice Sendak “Boy Measuring Tadpole” from Mysterious Tadpole movie, based on book by Steven Kellogg “Uncle Holding Up Tadpole Jar” from Mysterious Tadpole movie, based on book by Steven Kellogg “Big Anthony meets Strega Nona” from Strega Nona movie, based on book by Tomie dePaola “Goldilocks approaches the bears’ house” from Goldilocks and the Three Bears movie, based on book by James Marshall “Winnie and Harriet as Fox” from Wings a Tale of Two Chickens movie, based on book by James Marshall “Goldilocks running from house” from Goldilocks and the Three Bears movie, based on book by James Marshall “Goldilocks and Squirrel” from Goldilocks and the Three Bears movie, based on book by James Marshall “Goldilocks in Tub” from Goldilocks and the Three Bears movie, based on book by James Marshall “Red Riding Hood walking in woods” from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall “Red Riding Hood in Woods with Wolf” from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall “Red Riding Hood jumping rope with Cats looking on” from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall “Red Riding Hood petting Cat” from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall “Wolf in Grandma’s Bed” from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall “Giovanni Juggling Sticks” from Clown of God movie based on book by Tomie dePaola “Wolf with Balloon going to Pig’s House” from Three Little Pigs movie, based on book by James Marshall “Three Little Pigs and Wolf on stage” from Three Little Pigs movie, based on book by James Marshall “Wolf on Roof” from Three Little Pigs movie, based on book by James Marshall Original drawings by animator to test movement in Three Little Pigs movie 1 of 2 known copies of the entire storyboard by animator Virginia Wilkos for production of the motion picture Three Little Pigs
    - “Winnie & Fox” from Wings: a Tale of Two Chickens movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1991
    - “The Scientist” from Moon Man movie, based on book by Tomi Ungerer, 1981
    - “Self Portrait” from Here Comes Cat! movie, based on book by Frank Asch, 1992
    - “Bear Under Tree” from Happy Birthday Moon movie, based on book by Frank Asch, 1985
    - “Harold draws Bird” from Harold’s Fairytale movie, based on book by Crockett Johnson, 1974
    - “The Wild Thing” signed by Rudolph Holan, from Where the Wild Things Are movie, based on book by Maurice Sendak, 1975
    - “Bakers around Pot” from In the Night Kitchen movie, based on book by Maurice Sendak, 1987
    - “Mickey in the Milk Bottle” from In the Night Kitchen movie, based on book by Maurice Sendak, 1987
    - “Boy Measuring Tadpole” from Mysterious Tadpole movie, based on book by Steven Kellogg, 1987
    - “Uncle Holding Up Tadpole Jar” from Mysterious Tadpole movie, based on book by Steven Kellogg, 1987
    - “Big Anthony meets Strega Nona” from Strega Nona movie, based on book by Tomie dePaola, 1978
    - “Goldilocks approaches the bears’ house” from Goldilocks and the Three Bears movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1993
    - “Winnie and Harriet as Fox” from Wings: a Tale of Two Chickens movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1991
    - “Goldilocks running from house” from Goldilocks and the Three Bears movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1993
    - “Goldilocks and Squirrel” from Goldilocks and the Three Bears movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1993
    - “Goldilocks in Tub” from Goldilocks and the Three Bears movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1993
    - “Red Riding Hood walking in woods” from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1992
    - “Red Riding Hood in Woods with Wolf” from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1992
    - “Red Riding Hood jumping rope with Cats looking on” from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1992
    - "Wolf in Grandma's Bed" from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1992
    - "Red Riding Hood petting Cat" from Red Riding Hood movie, based on book by James Marshall, 1992
    - "Giovanni Juggling Sticks" from The Clown of God based on book by Tomie dePaola, 1982
    - "Wolf with Balloon going to Pig's House" from Three Little Pigs based on book by James Marshall, 1989
    - "Three Little Pigs and Wolf on Stage" from Three Little Pigs based on book by James Marshall, 1989
    - "Wolf on Roof" from Three Little Pigs based on book by James Marshall, 1989
    - Storyboard for Three Little Pigs based on book by James Marshall and animated by Virginia Wilkos, 1991
    - Sketches (18) for Three Little Pigs based on book by James Marshall, undated